A Guide to the Architectural Drawings for Kinloch
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10551-d
Architectural Drawings for Kinloch 1929-1937
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10551-d
ca. 110 items
Browne, Dalgliesh, Gilpin, Paxton, Architects
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The architectural drawings were given to the University of Virginia Library by Browne, Dalgliesh, Gilpin, Paxton, Architects, Charlottesville, Virginia, on January 3, 1997.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 106 architectural drawings and one folder with the specifications, ca. 1934-1937, and undated, for additions and alterations to " Kinloch, " the home of Mr. & Mrs. Linton Massey in Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall Swain Wells(1900-1974), Charlottesville, Virginia, primarily in 1934, and John W. Stenhouse, Bethesda, Maryland, in 1937. Also present are architectural drawings, 1929, for alterations to the residence of David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells(see folders 1 & 2). Architectural drawings are grouped primarily according to size and name of architect for the two different residences and in chronological order within each folder.
Container List
- Architectural Drawings by Marshall S. Wells
  - Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, F.S. Details of Cornice & Balustrade on Portico, 1929 Aug 23 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Stairway Details, 1929 Sep 19 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Part F.S. Elevation of Dormer at Head (2 sheets) [Sheet #4], 1934 Nov 3 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, F.S. of 2 Louver Frames "West Gable" [Sheet #3], 1934 Nov 3 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Entrance North Porch - Revised, 1934 Nov 21 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Detail North Porch - Revised, 1934 Nov 21 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Details for Passage - Revised [Sheet #13], [1935?] Feb 15 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Library Details - Section Through Elliptic Head at Stairs [Sheet #8], n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Details for Passage, (2 sheets, one heavily damaged) [Sheet #13], n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Detail of Elliptic Head Arch in Dressing Room (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, New Pilasters For Old Book Case, n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Dresser for Dressing Room, n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Columns for Library Porch, n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Library Details [Sheet #12], n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Doors for Library & Passage [Sheet #9], n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Radiator Enclosure, n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Library Details - Typical Elliptic Arch [Sheet #6], n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Details of Library Elevation of Square Head of Elliptic Arch at Stairs [Sheet #7], n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Unidentified House plan on brown tracing paper, n.d. (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
- Architectural Drawings by John W. Stenhouse
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, F.S. Basement Window Details, 1937 Nov 4 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, F.S. Details of Veg. Cabinet Vents, 1937 Nov 15 (Box Folder 1 (Oversize Tray 69))
- Architectural Drawings by Marshall S. Wells
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #1 Windows & Doors in Front of House, 1929 Aug 6 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #2 First Floor Plan, 1929 Aug 6 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #3 Second Floor Plan, 1929 Aug 6 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #4 F.S. Base of Pilaster, 1929 Aug 23 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #6 Window Details, 1929 Aug 23 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #9 Fireplace Living Room, 1929 Aug 23 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #7 Elevation of Side Porch & Columns, 1929 Sep 2 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #8 Elevation of the End of the Living Room with Bay Window, F.S. Detail of Pilaster, 1929 Sep 2 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #10 Elevation of Doors, 1929 Sep 7 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #11 Section Through Front Portico & Other Details, 1929 Sep 7 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #12 Stairs & Plan Under the Stairs, 1929 Sep 19 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Elevation of Back Portico, Columns & Cornice, 1929 Sep 21 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Alterations to Residence for David Patterson, Cismont, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, F.S. of Door Reveal Between Hall & Living Room, F. S. Column Shaft & Base, 1929 Sep 24 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
- Architectural Drawings by John W. Stenhouse
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, F.S. D. of Basement Entrance, 1937 Nov 3 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, Elevations of Typical Window, Typical Cupboard, etc., 1937 Nov 15 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, Details of Roof at Basement Entrance (3 sheets), 1937 Nov 22 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, Details of Range Hood, 1937 Nov 25 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, F.S. Details of Cornice & Chair Rail in Dining Room, 1937 Dec 9 (Box Folder 2 (Oversize Tray 15))
- Architectural Drawings by Marshall S. Wells
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #1 Basement Plan, 1934 Feb (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S. Wells, Sheet #2 First Floor Plan, 1934 Mar 2 (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Sheet #3 Second Floor Plan, 1934 Mar 2 (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Sheet #4 South Elevation, 1934 Feb (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Sheet #5 North Elevation, 1934 Feb (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, F.S. Details of Exterior Door Frame Porch to Library, 1934 Oct 18 (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Schedule of Windows in the New Wall, 1934 Oct 18 (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Library Details, Sheets #1-5 and Sheets #9-11, one of eleven revised on Feb 15 (9 total sheets) (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Front Elevation on Tracing Paper, n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Elevation of Back Portico & Plan under Stair on Tracing Paper (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, [First Floor Plan](2 sheets), n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, 2 Radiator Fronts for Living Room, n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Wardrobe for Dressing Room Hall, n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Wardrobe for Dressing Room, n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, F.S. Key of Arch & Other Details, n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Plan North Entrance, n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Basement Stair (2 sheets), n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, F.S. Dormer Detail, n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, North & East Elevation (2 sheets), n.d. (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
  - Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by Marshall S Wells, Library Details - End & Side Elevations (Box Folder 3 (Oversize Tray 15))
- Architectural Drawings by John W. Stenhouse
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, First Floor Plan; Basement Plan; South Elevation; East Elevation; North Elevation; West Elevation; and Alterations to the Dining Room (7 sheets), 1937 Jul 30 (Box Folder 4 (Oversize Box M-20))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, First Floor Plan; Basement Plan; South Elevation; East Elevation; North Elevation; and West Elevation (6 sheets), 1937 Aug 28 (Box Folder 4 (Oversize Box M-20))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, First Floor Plan; Basement Plan; South Elevation; East Elevation; North Elevation; West Elevation; Alterations to the Dining Room; Elevations of Fresh Air Vent, Typical Window, Laundry, & Pantry; Details of Stairwell, Basement Entrance & Windows; and Plumbing & Heating for First Floor & Basement (11 sheets), 1937 Oct 12 (Box Folder 4 (Oversize Box M-20))
  - Addition to Residence for Linton R. Massey, Keswick, Albemarle County, Virginia, by John W. Stenhouse, First Floor Plan; Basement Plan; South Elevation; East Elevation; North Elevation; West Elevation; Alterations to the Dining Room; and Elevations of Fresh Air Vent, Typical Window, Laundry, & Pantry (9 sheets), 1937 Sep (Box Folder 4 (Oversize Box M-20))